<u>LinkedIn</u> (404) 247-7687

# **AKPOVOGHO "AJ" IGHERIGHE**

Data Science Software Engineer

I use Data Science, Machine Learning (ML), Data Mining, and Software Engineering to help businesses and people achieve complex goals. While exposed to what would become HTML in the early 1990s and, eventually, building websites for small businesses in college, my professional programing experience only began ~7 years ago when I began using python to automate financial modeling. This was soon followed by ~5 years learning Data Science and 3 years becoming a more web focused software engineer.

### **SKILLS**

Languages/Scripts: Typescript, JavaScript, Python, Bash, Zsh, Go, SQL, HTML, CSS, Sass

Frameworks/Packages: React, Bootstrap, Express, Skeleton, Django, Flask, Materialize, Gin

**Additional**: Pandas, Scikit-Learn, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite, JQuery, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, LXC/LXD, Data Visualization, Plotly, Virtual Machines, VMWare, KVM/Qemu, Ubuntu, Arch, Agile

### **KEY PROJECTS**

#### **Magic Meme Ball**

- Connects to giphy api to present random memes on-demand
- Built using React, Axios, JavaScript, and custom randomization functions

### **Book Management System - Backend**

- Went through Golang tutorial and implemented a backend SQL book management system in 4 hours
- Tested backend functionality using both Curl terminal commands and Postman GUI
- Plan to incorporate learnings into more robust, future project

## **iGarageSale**

- Created a full CRUD web store application
- Utilized HTML, CSS, Typescript, JavaScript, and Mongo's online service to provide simple, playful, but functional features

## **EXPERIENCE**

### FitsMoi | 2021 - Present

- Transitioning current WordPress site to modern responsive web application capable of delivering a more favorable user experience
- Crafted preliminary multi-dimensional matrix framework that will be converted into the startups proprietary ML-based product
- Developed a multipage eCommerce affiliate marketing application the startup will use to raise capital
- Employed HTML, Skeleton CSS, Sass, TypeScript, and JavaScript as part of the technology stack

## Co-Founder/Head of Technology/Lead Data Scientist | InvestBuddys | 2019 - Present

- Manage creation and maintenance of the company's FinTech product InvestGuard including acting as a subject matter expert (SME) across various data-related domains
- Communicate complex concepts, conclusions, and technology clearly and concisely to non-technical fellow co-founder, board, and key management
- Translate complex business requirement with appropriate context into smaller easier to understand programmatic problems and product features
- Created proprietary predictive algorithms able to automatically approve funding transactions and manage the InvestGuard social impact crowdfunding platform

### Partner | RedStone-NAVG | 2011 - Present

- Completed ~\$200M of middle-market Private Equity (PE) transactions in Independent Sponsor Partnership
- Created a proprietary PE transaction modeling tool using python and MS Excel
- Produced, in part thanks to various proprietary tools created over the years, private equity diligence data product valued in a deposition by an industry expert to be worth \$4 million
- Automated numerous processes such as backend capital raising process using python

## Founder | Zibneal Consulting | 2000 - 2011

- Created multi-faceted finance consulting business that reached \$1M in revenue in the first 18 months
- Developed unique presentation and modeling style later adopted and still used by several search funds, independent sponsors, private equity firms, and a SPAC today
- Applied agile project management best practices to better predict required work efforts and finish 90% od projects on time and within budget
- Combined linear regression and other mathematic concepts with advanced Excel modeling techniques, prior to learning Data Science and programming, to identify key trends and recurring patterns and used this as the basis for making client recommendations

### Analyst | McKinsey & Company | 1999 - 2000

- Helped several Fortune 50 companies increase operating efficiency by up to 50% and revenue by 10%+
- Worked as part of a team to solve complex, critical problems
- Owned, eventually, singular workstream with complete responsibility for it completion
- Refined soft skills through practice presenting results of analysis directly to senior client leadership
- Mastered use of Microsoft office suite especially PowerPoint, Excel, and Access to tell compelling data-driven stories

### **EDUCATION**

Computer Science 101 | Stanford University, Remote (edX) | currently enrolled through April 7, 2021

Software Engineering Immersive | General Assembly, Remote

Data Science Bootcamp | Thinkful, Remote

Data Science Masters | Acadgild, Remote

Mathematical Foundation For Machine Learning And AI | udemy.com, Remote

Python Django Dev to Deployment | udemy.com, Remote

The Complete Web Development Bootcamp | udemy.com, Remote

Bachelor of Business Administration | Goizueta Business School, Emory University, Atlanta, GA

Computer Science 101 And 102 using C++ and Unix | Computer Science Department | Emory University, Atlanta, GA